-我来晚了  -没事  宝贝  不怪你
- I was late! - It's okay, sweetie. It's not your fault.
我只想在盖瑞家再玩把游戏
I just wanted to play one more game at Gary's.
你做得很好  立即打了急救电话
Well, you did great. You called 911 right away.
-他好像死了  -爸爸没死
- He looked dead. - Daddy's not dead.
他会没事的  对吧
He's gonna be okay, right?
-他中风了  -不可能
- He had a stroke. - That's not possible!
CT扫描证实动脉瘤破裂了
Well, the CT confirmed a ruptured aneurysm.
得做手术止血
We have to operate to clip the bleeding
释放颅内压
and reduce intracranial pressure.
不  他六年前中过风
No, he had a stroke six years ago.
当时用了地尔硫卓
They put him on diltiazem.
我们会救治你爸爸的
We're gonna take good care of your dad.
纳吉·莫迪  28岁  左手有烧伤
Naja Modi -- 28 years old, suffered a burn to her left hand
煮饭时不小心伤到的
as a result of a cooking accident.
我和杰瑞德是在受罚吗
Are Jared and I being punished?
这个病例没什么意思吧
This is not a very interesting case, is it?
第一
Lesson one --
别在外科主任面前说
Don't suggest to the the head of surgery
跟着外科主任干活
that working with the head of surgery
就是在受罚
is form of punishment.
梅伦德斯医生非常不满意
Dr. Melendez is very unhappy with Jared
杰瑞德是如何回来工作的
for how he got his job back.
梅伦德斯医生也非常不满意我...
And Dr. Melendez is unhappy with me for t-taking --
休了两天假
taking two days off.
我觉得他不想谈这事  肖恩
I don't think he wants to talk about this, Shaun.
我太蠢了
I was an idiot.
在炉子上啊  肯定很烫
It's on the stove. Of course it's hot, right?
你肯定不相信我们见过多少这种事故
You wouldn't believe how often we see these types of accidents.
那蠢货还挺多的
Well, there are a lot of idiots.
现在要怎么处理  莫菲
Okay, what do we need to do here, Murphy?
表面二度烧伤
A superficial partial-thickness burn
可以保守处理
should be managed conservatively.
清理烧伤区域  用柔软的纱布清创
Cleanse the area, debride with soft gauze,
用抗菌原油敷料包好
and then cover with an antimicrobial petroleum dressing.
也就是说
All of which means,
留个小疤就会好了
this should heal with minimal scarring.
纳吉  你胸口疼吗
Naja, are you having chest pain?
我好像心脏病发了
I think I'm having a heart attack.
呼吸困难
It's hard to breathe.
尽可能放松
Just relax if you can.
给她输氧  做12导联心电图
Put her on oxygen, a 12 lead EKG,
并安排床边胸部X光片
and order a portable chest X-ray.
莫菲  走吧  快
Murphy, let's move. Come on.
她的生命体征很稳定
Her vitals are stable.
到底怎么回事
What the hell is going on here?
不知道
I don't know.
但很有意思
But it is interesting.
良     医
第一季  第十三集
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
首席翻译官
█ 网易见外
蛛网膜下腔出血  抽吸
We've got a subarachnoid hemorrhage. Suction.
得隔离动脉瘤
I need to isolate the aneurysm.
首席校对官
█ 人人译视界
可怜的孩子
Poor kid.
想象发现自己的爸爸成这样了
Imagine finding your dad like that.
翻 译     Z小花儿   八步半   Santolalla
我倒是真想那样死掉
Well, that's exactly how I want to die.
翻 译     viniiii     Lynn_宁
如果他父亲没挺下来
If the dad doesn't make it,
孩子会永远记得那个画面
the kid will always remember that moment --
留下心理创伤
be traumatized by it.
因为他爱他
Because he loves him.
校 对     Santolalla
没有任何人因自己的死而伤心...
The idea of dying without anybody getting hurt --
最令人悲伤的莫过于空荡荡的等候室
There's nothing sadder than an empty waiting room.
时间轴     海默迷妹念   海默迷姐查
好  看到了什么
Okay, what do you see?
后 期     斯人
前部交通动脉上有个肿胀物
A bulge on the anterior communicating artery.
对  破裂的动脉瘤中断了
Yeah, the ruptured aneurysm is compromising
总 监     夕橙
大脑额叶的供血
blood flow to the frontal lobe.
准备十一毫米的标准夹子
Prep an 11 millimeter standard clip.
┌
┐
└
┘
人人影视官方客户端
唯一下载渠道
app.YYeTs.com
你结婚了吗
Are you married?
┌
┐
└
┘
离了
Not anymore.
原来他比我还没眼光
Turns out he had even worse judgment than I did.
说到变态  你知道科利被调走了吗
Oh, speaking of creeps, you hear Coyle got transferred?
他被调走真是太好了
I'm so glad they shut him down.
是啊  我想也是
Well, yeah, I guess.
真希望他们把钱用在买小儿创伤舱上
Just wish they'd spent the money on a Pediatric Trauma Pod.
他升职了
They gave him a raise.
夹子
Clip.
心电图证实
The EKG confirmed
你当时没有心脏病发作
you weren't having a heart attack.
我不是装的
I-I wasn't faking.
我不会那么做
I wouldn't do that.
我们知道
We know.
图像也证实了
The imaging also confirmed
你的肺部炎症很严重
that you have considerable lung inflammation.
你会不会吸到了烟
Is it possible you inhaled smoke?
肯定是吸到了
I guess I must have.
当时油脂引起了一场小火
There was a minor grease fire.
现在怎么办
What happens now?
你得做支气管镜检查
You need a bronchoscopy.
要从你的喉部插入窥镜检查损伤情况
We put a camera down your throat to see how much damage there is
看看该如何修复
and what we need to do to repair it.
别担心  会给你麻醉的
But don't worry. You'll be sedated.
不要
Please don't.
抱歉
Oh, I'm -- I'm sorry.
必须做检查
The test is absolutely necessary.
检查没问题
The test is fine.
但是
But, um...
请别碰我  除非是治疗必须的
please don't touch me, except for medical purposes.
当然
Yeah, of course.
没道理啊
That does not make sense.
很多宗教信仰对触碰都有规矩的
A number of religions have rules about touching.
我不太理解  但
I don't quite get it, but --
这有道理
That makes sense.
除非有很合理的原因
People shouldn't touch people
是不该触碰他人
unless there's a very good reason.
好  那么...
Okay, then...
是什么没道理
what doesn't make sense?
油脂起火
The grease fire.
油脂起火能解释所有情况
The grease fire explains the whole thing --
烧伤  烟
the burn, the smoke.
她说她忘了炉子很烫
She told us she forgot the stove was hot.
如果有东西着火了
How can you forget something's hot
怎么会忘了很烫
when it is on fire?
肖恩  如果她不是突然以为心脏病发了
Shaun, I'm sure we would have heard more of the story
我们肯定能听到更多内容
if she hadn't suddenly thought she was having a heart attack.
你为什么不炒了他
Why didn't you fire him?
因为他的说辞跟你的不一样
Because his story was different than yours.
而你信了他的说辞
And you believe his story?
我信了你的
I believe your story.
但你没证据
But you can't prove it.
而我们不能简单地制定政策
And we simply can't make a policy
相信每个投诉男人的女人
of believing every woman who files a complaint against every man.
数千年来一直不信女人的投诉
After a few thousand years of doing the opposite,
如今矫枉过正又有何不妥
it wouldn't kill us to overcorrect.
而你的男友打了他
And the fact that - your boyfriend assaulted him
让我没了任何筹码
took away any leverage I had.
我尽力了
I did what I could.
我把他调到了
I got him to take a position
很少能接触到其他职员和病患的职位
where he has very little contact with staff, with patients --
外联职位
outreach chair.
还是个很糟糕的调配
And it's a lousy assignment.
他迟早会辞职的
Sooner or later, he's gonna quit.
然后去其他地方工作
And get a job somewhere else.
如果你有更好的主意
If you have any better ideas...
我洗耳恭听
I look forward to hearing them.
你们很幸运
You're very lucky.
动脉瘤长在了一条小的交通动脉上
The aneurysm was in a small communicating artery.
我们成功修复了
We were able to restore blood flow
受阻大脑区域的供血
to the impacted brain areas.
他不会有事的
He's gonna be okay.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
之后会一直都这样吗
Is this what life is gonna be like from now on?
他会时不时病发吗
A-are these things just going to keep happening?
他会留院观察几天
We're gonna keep him here for a few days,
做些后续检查
do some follow-up testing,
调整一下他的用药
make some adjustments to his medications.
但愿能找到发病原因
Hopefully, we'll find out why this happened.
我得走了
I have to go.
又一个
Another one?
术后影像显示基底动脉上有个
Post-operative imaging showed a 26-millimeter aneurysm
26毫米的动脉瘤
in the basilar artery.
看这大小和位置
That size and location,
很有可能会破裂
we're looking at a high risk of rupture.
他肯定有遗传倾向性
He must have a genetic predisposition --
或许是结缔组织病
maybe a connective tissue disease?
在修复之前一切都是空谈
All academic till we repair it.
通过咽部
Through the pharynx
过去了  开始探险吧
and over - to Grandmother's house we go.
这是会厌和声带
There's the epiglottis and the vocal cords.
我知道你不满意我起诉了医院
I know you're not happy that I sued the hospital.
但我不会为此道歉的
But I'm not gonna apologize for that.
这就好办了
That makes it simple.
我这么做  是因为我想留在这
I did it because I want to be here.
我相信我能从你那学到很多东西
I believe I can learn a lot from you,
尽管受你冷落
even from your doghouse.
我只是希望你能给我一个机会
I just hope you give me a chance, sir.
这里是气管隆凸
There's the carina.
接下来要进入左主支气管
Gonna pass into the mainstem bronchus of the left lung.
和你未婚妻分手算得上创伤性事件吗
Is breaking up with your fiancée traumatic?
我看见那女人中枪的时候
When I saw a woman get shot,
所有人受说这是精神创伤
everyone told me it was traumatic
说我应该回家休息
and that I should be going home.
你不应该回家休息吗
Should you be going home?
给我一个黏膜刷取细胞样本
Give me a mucosal brush for a cellular sample.
这就插入黏膜刷
Loading it now.
从与爱人分手的痛苦中走出来
How long does it take to get over a breakup
需要多长时间
with the woman you love?
我看到了大面积炎症
I'm seeing a lot of inflammation,
但是没有油烟损伤
but no smoke damage.
这说得通
That makes se-sense.
我以为我们做这项检查是因为她吸入了油烟
I thought we were doing this because she inhaled smoke.
她说她吸入了油烟
She said she inhaled smoke.
我不相信她
I didn't believe her.
不管原因如何  炎症和损害是真实存在的
Whatever the cause, the inflammation and the damage are real.
咱们做个粘膜活检
Let's get a mucosal biopsy.
我要移动到这里  我们
I move down here, we --
气管镜穿破了她的支气管壁
The scope breached her bronchial wall.
她大出血了
She's hemorrhaging.
-太糟糕了  -准备手术
- This is bad. - Prep the O.R.!
交叉配血两个单位  我们快走
Type and cross two units of blood. We've gotta move!
烧伤是明确的
We know there was a burn.
气管损害是不是跟油火有关
Was it something related to the grease fire,
或者两者只是独立的巧合
or separate coincidental injury?
你是没有想法
You don't have a theory,
还是你不想和杰瑞德说话
or are you refusing to talk to Jared?
我不回答  是因为我觉得
I didn't answer because it doesn't matter
在我们修复穿孔
until we can repair this puncture
防止细菌进入并传播引起感染前  这不重要
before bacteria passes through and spreads an infection.
说的没错
That's true.
剪线
Cut this suture.
用镊子吻合切缘
Let's approximate the edges with forceps.
你和杰瑞德还在闹别扭吗
Are you and Jared even now?
他犯了个错误  你也是
He made a mistake. So did you.
我究竟犯了什么错误
Exactly what mistake did I make?
穿孔是你弄的
This breach was your fault.
这算精神创伤吗
Is that traumatic?
我自己吃的早餐
I had breakfast by myself.
你去哪了
Where were you?
抱歉  我们今早本来应该一起吃早餐是吗
I'm sorry. Were we supposed to have breakfast this morning?
我今早有个会诊
I had an early consult.
对  我们每周一都一起吃早餐
Yes, we always have breakfast on Mondays.
是吗  每周一
We do? Every Monday.
每周一
Every Monday.
谢谢
Thank you.
我猜我们的冷战已经告一段落了  是吗
Well, I guess our streak has been broken then, huh?
如果某人在常规支气管镜操作中
If someone punctures the bronchus
穿破了支气管  这算是错误  对吗
during a routine bronchoscopy, that's a mistake, right?
肯定是错误
Well, I can't imagine how it wouldn't be.
为什么这么问  你做了什么  肖恩
Why? What did you do, Shaun?
我想知道我是否要举报梅伦德斯医生
I'm wondering if I need to report Dr. Melendez.
梅伦德斯医生干的
Dr. Melendez did that?
规定写得很清楚
The protocol is very clear.
我得举报
I need to report it.
但是我看见他怎么对杰瑞德的
But I've seen how Jared is being treated.
如果我举报了梅伦德斯医生
Will Dr. Melendez treat me badly
他会不会也冷落我
if I report this?
显然  他不应该这样
He shouldn't, obviously.
但是人性就是这么...
But human nature being what...
人性
Human nature?
肖恩  你知道吗
Shaun, you know what?
这件事应该由你自己决定
You should make this decision for yourself.
其实  其实...
In fact -- In fact...
从现在开始  所有的决定都应该由你自己来做
you should to make - all your decisions yourself from here on in.
这是我们说好的  对吗
That's what we agreed on, right?
你有考虑过血管内栓塞术吗
Have you considered an endovascular embolization procedure?
考虑了
I have.
风险会降低
It's a little less risky,
但是我做得不多
but I haven't done as many,
所以我不确定怎么做比较好
so I'm not sure which way we're better off.
你是不是想让我查一下名单
You want me to check the roster --
看看有没有更有经验的医生能够胜任
see if there's somebody available with more experience?
是的  我可以从旁协助
I would like to assist, but yes.
好的  我们来看看
Okay, here we go.
不  他没法做
No, he's not available.
那就想方设法让他做
So make him available.
身为人夫和人父
I got a husband and father
他在过去的十二小时里已经出现两个动脉瘤了
who presented with two aneurysms in the last 12 hours.
最好不要
I'd rather not.
那位外科医生最近被...
This particular surgeon was recently...
调职了
transferred.
没门
Not a chance.
科利是这项手术的最佳人选
Coyle is the best available surgeon for the job.
科利本应该被解雇  如果他被解雇了
Coyle should've been fired, and if he'd been fired,
他根本不可能来做这手术
he wouldn't be available.
如果他不能做
And if he wasn't available,
你将会是这项手术的最佳人选
you would be the best person for the job.
我们应该以患者为重
Our ultimate duty is to the patient.
不  不是
No, it's not.
你同意他应该被解雇
You agree he should have been fired.
当然
Of course.
就算他是这家医院里最好的医生
Even if he was the - best doctor in this hospital,
他也应该被解雇  对吗
he should have been fired, right?
对
Yes.
所以有些事情
So some things have to matter more
比谁的手术技术高超更重要
than who is the most skilled.
如果科利擅长于某些领域  就能因此得到原谅
If we forgive Coyle just because he's good at something,
他接下来会做些什么
what does he do next?
要么选他  要么选我们
Either he matters or we matter.
你在手术过程中感到烦恼吗
Were you upset during the procedure?
莫菲告诉你我有「精神创伤」了
Did Murphy tell you that I was "Traumatized"?
你觉得我差点害死了一个人
You think that I might have almost killed a person
都是因为你甩了我
because you dumped me?
事实上  你把这件事说成「我甩了你」
The fact that you're describing it as "Me dumping you"
恰恰说明你为此心烦意乱
suggests that you are upset.
听着  我没事  你也没事
Look, I'm fine. You're fine.
没人为此烦心
Nobody's upset.
很好
Great.
但是你要明白
But you do understand
我必须得问你这些问题
that I have to ask you these questions,
因为我需要你给个说法
that I need a statement from you.
明白
Yes.
这就是我的说法
Here's my statement --
「我没有分心
"I wasn't distracted.
我没有搞砸」
I didn't screw up."
你听明白了吧
You get all that?
你的支气管在手术过程中发生了穿孔
Your bronchus was punctured during the procedure,
不过穿孔已经修复好了
but it's been repaired.
什么  怎么会这样
How? How could that happen?
为什么说谎
Why did you lie?
你说你吸入了油烟
You said that you inhaled smoke,
但支气管里根本没有油烟
but there was no evidence of smoke.
所以向你的医生撒谎  你能得到什么好处
So, what do you gain by lying to your doctors?
我没有撒谎
I wasn't lying.
我只是...
I was just...
迷糊了  我想
confused, I guess.
我很痛
I was in a lot of pain,
而且一切发生的太快了
and it was all happening so fast.
我的胃
My stomach!
纳吉  你有什么感觉
Naja, what are you feeling?
真的很痛...  我感觉我要
It's really sore and... I feel like I'm going to--
这里需要帮助
Can we get some help over here?!
四毫克昂丹司琼
Four milligrams of ondansetron.
气道炎症  腹痛  恶心
Airway inflammation, abdominal pain, nausea.
我们需要做全套血液化验和腹部超声
We need a full blood panel and abdominal ultrasound.
手术会夹闭动脉瘤
The procedure will seal off the aneurysm,
但很有可能会造成一些脑损伤
but there will almost certainly be some brain damage --
从轻微的视觉障碍或语言障碍
anything from mild visual or speech disturbances
到严重的瘫痪  都有可能
to significant paralysis.
但不做手术  他会死
But without the surgery, he'll die.
不  我不同意做手术
No. I-I won't consent to the operation.
你没有太多选择的余地
There really isn't a lot of choice here.
不做手术
Without the operation --
在他第一次中风后
After his first stroke, it --
他花了很长时间才恢复过来
it took him so long to recover.
对他来说  这个过程非常痛苦沮丧
It was frustrating and painful for him.
但是他最终恢复过来了
But he did recover.
他很清楚  他不想生活在妥协中
He made it clear he'd never want to live compromised.
抱歉
Excuse me.
谢谢你和我一起吃早餐
Thank you for having breakfast with me.
这是我的荣幸
My pleasure.
人们经常撒谎  对吗
People lie a lot, don't they?
不  我是认真的  肖恩
No, I-I meant it, Shaun.
我很开心能和你共度时光
I'm happy to spend time with you.
我想到了七个原因
There are seven reasons that I've thought of.
也许还有更多
There may even be more.
人们会毫无理由地撒谎吗
Do people ever lie without a reason?
不会
No.
第六个原因  我认为你刚刚撒谎了
Reason number six. I think you just lied.
我认为你刚为了逃避某些事而撒谎
I think you just lied to avoid something.
你不喜欢这番对话
You don't like this conversation.
肖恩  我很抱歉
Shaun, n-- Shaun, I'm sorry.
我只是有点分心
I'm just -- just a little distracted.
我的那位动脉瘤病人
My aneurysm patient --
我们在给他用高血压药
We're treating him with blood-pressure meds
避免他动脉破裂
to try and avoid a rupture.
你们应该采用血管内栓塞
You should do - an endovascular embolization.
他并不想要
He doesn't want one.
会给他的大脑造成损害
It could leave him with brain damage.
我以为他没有意识
I thought he was unconscious.
是的
He is.
他的妻子知道他想要什么
His wife knows what he wants.
太令人惊讶了
It's amazing. I just --
我不认为我能做到像她那样
I don't think I'd be able to do that.
她牺牲了自己的幸福和未来
She's sacrificing her happiness, her future,
就因为她知道
just because she knows --
她在撒谎
She's lying.
可能是由于原因四或者是
It could be either reason number four or --
不  她没有在撒谎  肖恩  她爱他
No, she's not lying, Shaun. She loves him.
她不爱他
She doesn't love him.
你都没有见过她
You haven't even met her!
你没见过她和他还有他们儿子一起的样子
You haven't seen what she's like with him, with their son.
我不善于洞悉他人
I'm not good at reading people.
-我善于  -我认为洞悉他人
- Well, I am, and - I think people-reading
总会包含自己的偏见
embraces personal biases.
我认为我们应该避免偏见
I think we should try to avoid biases.
了解他人的表现
Knowledge of human behavior
可以让我们做出有见地的  直觉的决定
can help us make - informed, intuitive decisions.
我的方法更好
My way is better.
基于行为之上  她是在撒谎
It's based on actions. She's lying.
好吧
All right.
如果你爱一个人
If you love someone,
你会不遗余力阻止他死去
you'll do anything to prevent their death.
这个情况
This...situation --
可能会产生利益冲突
There seems to be a conflict of interest.
所以我想派一个法律上的第三方
So I would like to bring in someone else from legal
来处理它
to handle it.
我同意
Yeah, I agree.
你是位杰出的律师  但是
You're an excellent lawyer, but --
但是什么
But what?
你认为这是我的问题吗
Do you think this is my problem?
这合乎情理
It's understandable.
48小时前我们才订婚
48 hours ago, we were engaged.
现在突然
And now, suddenly,
你就要来调查我
you're supposed to be investigating me?
是的
Yes.
还有更疯狂的事
And doing crazy things,
比如期待你会给合适的问题
like expecting you to give me complete answers
一个完整的答案
to appropriate questions.
你相信墨菲的判断而不相信我的
You were trusting Murphy's judgment over mine.
他做出的关于本人举止的判断
His judgment about my demeanor.
真的吗
Seriously?
我就问了你一个问题
I asked you a question.
你想要我完蛋
You wanted me to screw up.
你确实弄砸了
You did screw up.
所以又怎样
So what?
我们只要处理它就好了
So we just deal with it.
但如果你不承认你无法一直完美
But if you can't even admit that you're not always perfect,
我不完美
then I -- - I am not perfect!
很明显  我的人生里也犯过错
Clearly, I have made mistakes in my life.
但这次不是我的错
But not this time.
刺破支气管不是我的错
That punctured bronchus was not my fault.
护士说他的生命体征稳定
The nurse says his vital signs are stable.
没有变化
No change.
很好
That's good.
这是
It's...
很大的牺牲
such a great sacrifice
尊敬他的愿望到甘愿让他离开
to respect his wishes enough to let him go.
你肯定很爱你的丈夫
You must love your husband very much.
但是
But...
也可能会有其他的解释
there could be another explanation.
你可能是爱他到愿意让他死去
Either you love him enough to let him die...
又或者是恨他到想让他死去
or you hate him enough to let him die.
你根本不知道你在说什么
You don't know - what you're talking about.
这里有一个医生曾经骚扰过我
There's a doctor here who harassed me.
他让我觉得自己很脆弱并且毫无价值
He made me feel vulnerable, worthless --
其实我并不是这样
neither of which I am.
但他没有伤害过我
But he never hurt me.
我无法想象如果他伤害了我
I can't imagine how I would feel if he did,
我会做什么
what I would do,
我会想对他做什么
what I would want to do to him.
你的丈夫对你做了什么
What did your husband do to you?
他是个好父亲
He's a good father.
不  他不是
No, he's not.
好父亲不会伤害母亲
A good father doesn't hurt a mother.
佩顿很爱他
Payton loves him.
所有的原因
All the more reason --
不
No.
佩顿什么也不知道  他永远不能知道
Payton doesn't know anything. He never can.
我知道你害怕他会来找你
I know you're afraid he'll come after you,
但有人能够帮助你
but there are people who can help.
家庭暴力
拥有一个慈父的记忆对佩顿来说
Payton is better off with the memory of a loving father
比知道真相更好
than the truth.
让他死吧
Let him die.
甲醇造成她腹部疼痛
Methanol is causing her abdominal pain.
她是喝了木酒精吗
She drank wood alcohol?
人们能喝什么就喝什么
People drink whatever they can drink.
她是穆斯林  不愿意让我碰她
Well, she's Muslim -- Wouldn't let me touch her.
有宗教信仰的人并不对伪善免疫
Religious people aren't immune to hypocrisy.
甲醇的存在也可能有其他原因
There are other ways to explain the presence of methanol.
肝脏也会产生甲醇
It's also produced by the liver
当身体接触到腐蚀性化学物质
when the body is exposed to certain caustic chemicals.
如果被吸入  腐蚀性物质也会刺激肺部
If inhaled, caustic chemicals could also inflame the lungs.
腐蚀性物质还会燃烧
And caustic chemicals also burn,
这就解释了她所有症状
so it would explain all her symptoms.
你有没有能造成所有这些后果的
Do you happen to have a list
腐蚀性物质的清单
of which caustic chemicals do all that?
硫酸二甲酯
Dimethyl sulfate
被用于药业
It's used in - the pharmaceutical industry.
她是学校教师
She's a school teacher.
它也用于水处理  农药工业
It's also used in water treatment, industrial pesticides,
以及化学武器
and chemical weapons.
她没有理由参与到
She has no reason to be involved
水处理或农药工业中
with water treatment or industrial pesticides.
但她可以同时是教师和恐怖分子
But she could be a school teacher and a terrorist.
-所以我们该怎么办  -做手术
- So, what do we do? - The surgery.
我们没有得到她的同意
We don't have her consent.
严格意义上  我们是没有得到他的同意
Technically, the issue is we don't have his consent.
我们找他的妻子是因为得不到他的同意
We go to his wife because we can't get his,
猜想是她在为了他的利益最大化考虑
the assumption being that she's operating in his best interests.
但我不会让这发生
Pretty sure that's not happening here.
去找他的妻子  改变她的主意
Go back to the wife, get her to change her mind,
不然我们就上法庭
or we'll take it to court.
好的
Okay.
你看上去很烦恼
Hey, you look annoyed.
我担心我们把他送回家他会继续家暴她
I'm annoyed we're sending him home to keep abusing his wife.
她是个一流的骗子
She's a world-class liar.
就我们所知  她希望她的丈夫死掉
I mean, for all we know, she wants her husband dead
她就可以和她的普拉提教练私奔
so that she can run off with her Pilates instructor.
-我会让她同意的  -谢谢
- I'll get the consent. - Thank you.
她拒绝甲醇中毒的初步治疗
She refused initial treatment for methanol toxicity.
是乙醇
It's ethanol --
因为她是穆斯林  她不能使用乙醇
Because she's Muslim, she can't consume it.
她体内本就有酒精
She has alcohol in her system
她却不愿意将酒精输送到体内进行治疗
but won't let us put alcohol in her system to treat it,
因为她不想自己体内有酒精
because she doesn't want alcohol in her system.
-我们对她注射了甲  -墨菲医生
- We put her on fomepi - Dr. Murphy...
你凭此就认为她是恐怖分子
Is this part of your evidence that she's a terrorist?
因为她是穆斯林吗
Because she's Muslim?
有成千上万的穆斯林不是恐怖分子
There are billions of Muslims that aren't terrorists.
你凭此认为她就不是恐怖分子吗
Is that part of your evidence that she's not?
我认为她是恐怖分子  因为这是最佳的解释
I think she's a terrorist because it's the easiest way
对于她的症状和谎言
to explain her symptoms and her lie.
你有办法解释吗
Do you have a way?
她出了事故  吓坏了她
She had an accident. It scared her.
也许是我们吓坏了她  也许这个地方吓坏了她
Maybe we scare her. Hell, maybe this whole place scares her.
除了犯罪活动之外
There are a lot of reasons people don't tell the truth
还有很多理由会导致人们不说实话
other than criminal activity.
别的六个理由
Six other reasons.
如果一个人入院的时候身上有枪伤
If a person comes in with a gunshot wound,
我们得上报
we have to report it.
为什么有人可能在研制化学武器
Why don't we have to report
我们却不必上报呢
someone who might be making chemical weapons?
因为毫无根据的指控是会毁掉别人的
Because unfounded accusations can destroy people's lives.
只要真相水落石出
What does it matter what people speculate
那人们推测什么又有什么关系呢
as long as the truth comes out?
因为人们在真相水落石出之前
Because people make up their minds
就已经做出了决断
before the truth comes out.
这话是从一个老打种族牌
Says the guy who played the race card
占便宜的人口中说出的
when he needed an advantage.
即使你说的是对的
Even if you're right,
当她在重症监护室的时候也并没有制造炸弹
she's not making bombs while she's in our ICU.
还有你是错的  现在  有什么消息通知我
Also, you're wrong. Now, keep me posted.
如果她在接下来的两个小时没有好转
If she's not better in the next two hours,
告诉我
I want to know.
我们需要你同意我们给你丈夫手术
We need you to consent to your husband's surgery.
我说过了  「不」
I said "No."
还有一种更好的办法  泰莎
There's a better way, Tessa.
离开他
Leave him.
开始新的生活
Start a new life.
我害怕
I'm afraid.
我懂
I know.
但是这...
But...this --
这不是回答
This isn't the answer.
如果你不同意
If you don't consent,
我们会把这个送到法院
we'll take this to the court,
把我们知道的都告诉法官
and we'll tell a judge what we know.
我是偷偷告诉你这些的
I told you those things in confidence.
你不是我的病人  你丈夫是
You are not my patient. Your husband is.
有两种可能
Two things will happen.
我们得到许可
We will get the consent,
佩顿会知道真相
and Payton will find out the truth.
泰莎
Tessa?
你比你想的要更坚强
You are stronger than you think you are.
你体内甲醇的毒性在减轻...
Your methanol toxicity is abating --
治疗有效果了
The treatment's working.
很好
Great.
你觉得我用不了多久就可以离开了吗
Do you think that I'll be able to leave soon?
你的所有症状都符合
All of your symptoms are consistent
接触硫酸二甲脂的症状
with exposure to dimethyl sulfate.
我  我从来都没听过什么硫酸二...
I -- I've never heard of dimethyl --
硫酸二甲脂被用来做化学武器
Dimethyl sulfate is used to make chemical weapons.
我没想到这话是从你嘴里说出来的
I didn't expect this from you.
我表达了我的意见
I made a statement.
你不一样
You're different.
我有自闭症
I have autism.
你体会过人们对你有偏见的滋味
You've experienced bigotry.
是的
Yes.
你有被人拒绝服务过吗
Have...people refused to serve you?
你有看到过人们
Have you seen people
因为你
change their flight
更改航班吗
because of you?
你有经历过人们在你开口之前
Have people cursed you out
就对你恶语相向吗
before you've opened your mouth?
我没有偏见
I'm not prejudiced.
我有证据
I have evidence.
没有人有偏见
Nobody's prejudiced.
大家都有证据
Everybody has evidence.
而我一直都是棕色人种
And I'm always brown.
也许你没那么不同
Maybe you're not so different.
你在出汗
You're sweating.
出汗是说谎的一个迹象
Perspiration is a sign of dishonesty.
我的胸
My chest.
胸痛可能是由焦虑引起
Chest pain can be brought on by anxiety.
但这次  你是心脏病发作了
Oh, but this time, you are having a heart attack.
心电图  立刻
EKG, stat!
血管内皮膜缓和了急性炎症
The endothelial lining had moderate inflammation that appeared acute,
有粘膜水肿的迹象
and there was evidence of mucosal edema.
我没有做任何特别的处理
I made no extraordinary motions,
也没有采取任何不必要的措施
nor did I apply any unnecessary force.
然而支气管被刺穿了
And yet, the bronchus was punctured.
这是这种手术的风险
Which is a risk, albeit a small one,
尽管可能性不大
with this kind of procedure.
好吧...
Well...
谢谢
thank you.
感谢你耐心回答我的问题
I appreciate the thoroughness of your answers.
虽然我也不确定我都明白了...
Not sure I understood it all...
但是我想我已经得到我需要的了
...but I think I've got what I need.
我可能不该说什么
I probably shouldn't say anything,
但我知道你和普莱斯顿女士
but I know you and Ms. Preston
现在正经历一些事
are going through something right now.
那和这一点关系都没有
That really wasn't relevant.
我  我知道  我知道  只是...
I-I know. I know. It's just...
我知道她会挺过去的  但...
I know she'll get through it, but...
你处理得更好是件好事
it's good you're handling it better.
在起草合同的时候被分心是一回事
It's one thing to be distracted while drafting a contract
你所做的又是另外一回事了
and a whole other thing entirely doing what you do.
注入染色剂
Inject dye.
Injecting dye.
挂在左脊椎动脉上
Hanging a left at the vertebral artery.
好了  撤回导线
Okay, withdrawing the guide wire.
插入白金色基体
Inserting the platinum matrix.
你知道吗  有的时候  你做了正确的事
You know, sometimes, you do the right thing
事情会变得更好
and things get a little better.
有的时候  事情依旧糟糕
And sometimes, things still suck.
进入动脉瘤
Entering the aneurysm.
好了
Okay.
血压上升
Blood pressure's spiking.
等等  为什么
Wait, why?
没有破裂  没有出血
There's no rupture, no bleeding,
没有中风
no stroke.
如果血压再高点  他就要中风了
If his BP goes up any higher, he will have a stroke.
我现在要停止手术了
I'm terminating the procedure.
立刻推20毫克拉贝洛尔
Push 20 milligrams of labetalol, stat.
在再次手术之前我们得让他稳定下来
We need to stabilize him before we can retry the procedure,
也就是说我们得弄清楚我们漏掉了什么
which means we need to figure out what we missed.
这不是我们的错
This wasn't our fault.
他进手术室的时候血压是稳定的
His BP was stable going in.
过去的六年里他一直服用钙离子阻断剂
He's been on calcium-channel blockers for the last six years.
我们漏掉了什么
Well, we missed something.
血压不会无缘无故就猛涨的
BP doesn't skyrocket for no reason.
做个全面检查
Run a full work-up.
为什么一个28岁的没有任何风险因素的人
Why would a 28-year-old with no risk factors
会有心脏病
have a heart attack?
她的心脏在燃烧
Her heart is burning.
燃烧
Burning?
因为腐蚀性化学物质
From the caustic chemical!
-莫菲  -穿过了她整个系统
- Murphy. - It's going through her system.
不像烧烫伤
Unlike thermal burns,
化学灼伤随着时间会越来越严重
chemical burns get worse over time.
这也解释了她的支气管为什么会穿孔
And it also explains the punctured bronchus.
腐蚀性化学物质使支气管壁变薄
The caustic chemical thinned the bronchial walls.
你没有犯错
You did not make a mistake.
那不是唯一的解释
That's not the only explanation.
但我现在就闭嘴
But I'll shut up now.
你觉得你有个好主意
You think you have a good idea,
但是你准备不说出来
but you're going to shut yourself up?
有可能是由
It could be caused by an infection
支气管穿孔导致的
from bacteria that leaked
细菌感染造成的
as a result of the puncture.
如果是感染的话  治疗的方式是完全相反的
The treatments are diametrically opposed --
如果是感染的话应该输注抗生素
antibiotics if it's infection,
如果是发炎的话应该输注类固醇
steroids if it's inflammation.
如果她需要抗生素  而不是类固醇
If she needs antibiotics and she needs steroids instead,
会抑制她的免疫系统
it will suppress her immune system,
加重感染  使她丧命
causing the infection to flourish and kill her.
如果她需要类固醇
If she needs steroids
而我们给她输注抗生素  那么...
and we give her antibiotics, then --
我明白
I get it.
我们最好是对的
We'd better be right.
是的
Yes.
先生  我们应该再找一位高级主治医生参与
Sir, I think we should bring another senior attending in
-商量这个决定  -为什么
- to consult on this decision. - Why?
因为如果肖恩是对的  你就没做错
Because if Shaun's right, you're exonerated.
如果我是对的  你可能犯了一个
And if I'm right, you may have made the mistake
可能会杀了这位女士的错误
that could kill this woman.
你觉得我不能保持客观
You don't think I can be objective?
我认为你非常专业...
I think you're incredibly professional --
闭嘴  杰瑞德
Shut up, Jared.
有可能是我搞砸了
It is possible that I screwed up.
给她输注广谱抗生素
Let's put her on broad-spectrum antibiotics.
你错了
You're wrong.
在你犯错的前提下做决定是个错误
Making a decision on the assumption you made a mistake is a mistake.
你很自大
You're very arrogant.
这帮你成为更好的外科医生
It helps you be a great surgeon.
万幸的是  我用不着你来批准
Fortunately, I don't need your approval.
我们确定了潜在的问题
We've determined what the underlying problem was.
是什么导致了你丈夫的动脉瘤破裂
What caused your husband's aneurysm to rupture
以及他在手术室血压下降的缘由
and why his blood pressure spiked in the O.R.
数据显示  他没有在服用药物
According to his labs, he hasn't been taking his meds.
据我所知  他有吃药
As far as I know, he has.
这不像他
I mean, that's just not like him.
我们也觉得不是他
We don't think it's like him, either.
你们觉得是我做了手脚
You think I had something to do with this?
怎么  我扔了他的药吗
That I, what, threw his meds away?
他会再订一些
He'd just order more.
但如果你清空了他的胶囊  并换成糖
But if you emptied his capsules and filled them with sugar --
或者更好  换成盐
or, even better, salt --
这会结束你的噩梦
It would end your nightmare.
我很愿意让他死
I was willing to let him die,
但我怎么可能...
but I could never --
如果我足够勇敢去杀他...
If I were strong enough to kill him...
有没有可能  你儿子知道得比你以为的多
Is there a chance your son knows more than you think he does?
她的心率是90
Her heart rate's 90.
这在正常范围内
That's in the normal range.
但之前是83  应该降低才对
But it was 83. It should be going down.
她其它体征都正常
All her other signs are normal.
你是对的  这是妥善处理
You were right. This is the proper treatment.
95了
95.
我要换成类固醇
I'm switching her to steroids.
如果给她注射类固醇
If we give her steroids,
那会抑制她的免疫系统
it will suppress her immune system,
导致严重感染
causing the infection to flourish...
我要注射40毫克甲基强的松龙
I'm going to push 40 milligrams of methylprednisolone.
进而死亡
...and she'll die.
我来承担
This is on me.
我知道
I know.
我们给她换成了甲基强的松龙
We switched her to methylprednisolone.
起作用了
It's working.
你错了
You were wrong.
是的  我知道了
Yeah, I got that.
只是治疗方案错了
Just about the treatment choice.
你在手术室里没做错
You didn't do anything wrong in the O.R.
别拍我马屁了
Don't kiss my ass.
杰瑞德救了她
Jared saved her life.
如果他没有迅速采取措施  她可能就死了
If he hadn't acted so quickly, she would've died,
而那是你的错
and that would've been your fault.
是的  没错
Yes, it would've.
你应该感谢他
You should thank him.
谢谢你  卡卢医生
Thank you, Dr. Kalu.
有什么事吗
Can I help you?
我是肖恩·莫菲医生
I'm Dr. Shaun Murphy.
你是我的新邻居  34号
You're my new neighbor, number 34.
好吧
Yeah, cool.
你想进来喝瓶酒吗
You wanna come in for a beer?
不了
No.
干得不错
Nice work.
你也是
You, too.
功劳属于你
You can have the honors.
这是第一次  我不想告诉家人
This is the first time I'm not looking forward
手术进行得很顺利
to telling the family it went well.
你会没事的
You're going to be fine.
治疗见效了
The treatment worked?
第二次的见效了  第一次的差点害死你
The second one did. The first one almost killed you.
你现在还活着
The fact that you're alive right now is evidence
就证明你接触了硫酸二甲酯
that you were working with dimethyl sulfate.
你是恐怖分子  是不是
You're a terrorist, aren't you?
我哥哥在药厂工作
My brother works for a drug company.
他们用硫酸二甲酯来制药
They use dimethyl sulfate to make one of their medications.
他替我偷了一些
He stole some for me.
让你来做化学武器
So you could make a chemical weapon.
让我做香水
So I could make perfume.
你闻
Smell that.
很好闻
It's...beautiful.
但很蠢
But very stupid.
是啊
Yeah.
尤其当我哥哥随时可能被炒鱿鱼
Especially since my brother would get fired
如果有人发现这事
if anyone ever found out.
你相信她
You believe her?
保护某人
Protecting someone --
第三种理由
reason number three.
我们还好吗
So...we good?
问题是  我不确定这是否重要
Thing is, I'm not sure it really matters.
我被告知  我明年只能有三位住院医师
I've been told I can only have three residents next year.
这太好了
That's great.
算不上
Not really.
因为科利走了  我得接手他的
Because of Coyle's transfer, I have to take on his.
雷兹尼克
Reznick?
她可让人头痛
She's a pain.
头痛也可以转化为动力
Pain can be a hell of motivator.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你是对的
You were right.
你是对的  而我希望你错了
And I think you were right that I wanted you to be wrong.
我很抱歉
And I'm sorry.
你也没错
You were right, too.
我一直告诉自己  我没事  但...
I kept telling myself that I'm fine, but...
这很艰难
it's been hard.
让我怀疑自己
Got me second-guessing myself,
也许影响了我的判断
maybe affecting my judgment.
我说不好
I don't know.
如果我们这么难过  也许我们做错了
If we're hurting so bad, maybe we made a mistake.
不
No.
这只是说明我们的曾经很重要
It just means that what we had mattered.
不代表那是对的
Doesn't mean that it was right.
我也在想...
I've also been thinking that...
自大让我成为了更好的外科医生
arrogance does make me a better surgeon.
但不会让我成为更好的丈夫
But it's not gonna make me a better husband.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
克丽丝汀吗
Kristin?
我是克莱尔
I'm Claire.
谢谢你
Thanks.
我在调查科利医生
I am doing some research on Dr. Coyle --
调查和他共事但辞职的女人
on the women who worked with him and then quit.
我接到了市区交通的工作邀请
I got another offer at SF Muni.
我被科利医生骚扰了
I was harassed by Dr. Coyle.
我觉得你也是
And I think you were, too.
做正确的事  能让事情变得更好
Doing the right thing can make things a little better...
尤其当我们一起做的时候
especially if we do it together.
我有新邻居了
I have a new neighbor.
这么说莉亚真的走了
So, Lea's really gone, huh?
我们明天能一起吃早餐吗
So, can we have breakfast tomorrow?
我很想去  肖恩  但是...
I'd love to, Shaun, but...
我们...
we...
我们谈过了
We talked about this, right?
我说了如果你留下  我不会继续紧逼
I-I said that I would back off if you stayed, right?
给你更多空间  不再试图当你的父亲
More space, less "Fathering."
我不需要父亲
I don't need a father.
我讨厌父亲
I hate fathers.
是的  所以...
Right, so --
我需要朋友
I need a friend.
肖恩  我忍不住会给他人建议  你明白吗
Shaun, I-I am someone who can't help but give advice, you know?
我不知道自己能否做到
I don't know if I can not do that.
所以你觉得我能改变  但你不能
So you think I can change and you can't?
我觉得我们的关系很特殊
I think that we have a certain kind of relationship.
如果我们愿意  可以将之称其为其它的
And we can call it something different if we want,
但我们无法改变它
but we can't magically make it different.
你说了你想要空间
You said that you wanted space.
你说你需要空间
You said that you needed space.
我觉得你应该当我的朋友
I-I think you should be my friend.
肖恩
Shaun...
好的
Okay.
肖恩
Shaun?
BGM: Broken by Patrick Watson
♪ Do you feel a little broken? ♪
♪ Do you feel a little bro-o-ken? ♪
♪ Memories come and they go ♪
♪ You just learn to let go ♪
♪ Sometimes, sometimes, you wanna, wanna go back ♪
你现在闻到什么了
What are you smelling right now?
松树
Pine trees.
♪ Do you feel a little broken? ♪